Hello, and welcome back. We are going to now give an example of
【未完成版本】 欢迎回来 现在我们将用一个例子说明
Calculus of variations used in image processing, and these are the techniques
变分法在图像处理中的应用 这些技术
we just saw in the previous video. Let's apply them to image processing now.
都在前面的视频中出现过 让我们开始吧
And we're going to do that with one of the most famous equations in image
我们将使用到 基于偏微分方程的图像处理领域中
processing, in the area of partial differential equations in image
最著名的方程之一
processing, and that's Anisotropic Diffusion.
那就是 各向异性扩散 (Anisotropic Diffusion)
What is that? If you remember, when we discussed the
这是什么呢？ 回忆一下 在我们讨论
Gaussian filtering and averaging images, we talked that those are, were like
高斯滤波和图像平均时 曾提到过
diffusion of the pixel values all across the image.
这两种方法相当于将像素值扩散到整幅图像
What was happening is that we obtained blurring.
那样做的结果是模糊的图像
Because if there were edges basically, we were averaging across edges.
因为如果图像中有边界 而我们是跨边界求平均
We were letting the pixels' values across edges to be basically mixed up and that's
使得边界两侧原本差异巨大的像素值进行混合 也就产生了
when we obtained blurry. And that was Isotropic Smoothing.
模糊 那是各向同性平滑(Isotropic Smoothing)
It was just going all around. It didn't matter if it had boundaries or
各向同性平滑是不考虑所平滑的范围内是否有边界
not boundaries. What Anisotropic Smoothing or Anisotropic
而各向异性平滑或
Diffusion is trying to do is going to try to average pixels value, pixel values,
扩散要做的 是考虑对象中的边界后 在边界的某一侧对
only on the right side of the object, on the right side of the edge, on the
像素值进行平均
correct object. So, pixel values here are going to be
如此 平均只会发生在值较接近的像素群中
averaged among themselves, to basically denoise or enhance the image.
这本身就是去噪声或图像增强的过程
Pixel values here are going to be basically mixed among themselves.
被平均的像素值并无巨大差异
How do we do that? We do that with equations,
如何实现 使用方程来实现
partial differential equations as we see here. Before we look at the equations,
就是这里的偏微分方程 在看方程之前
let us look at the images, this is an original image.
先看图像 这是原图
And if we do basically, Gaussian Smoothing or Averaging, we know that we
假如对原图使用高斯平滑或平均 我们知道图像会
are going to blur. We blur across the boundaries because
变模糊 因为高斯平滑
it's just mixing pixels from different objects and that's what we see here.
是不区分边界的对所有像素值进行平均 所以会模糊对象的边界 这里可以看到结果
On the other hand, if we try not to blur, try not to mix, we only mix pixels on the
如果我们不想模糊边界 那只能先区分边界 并只对边界的某一侧像素
same side of the boundary without going in this direction, then we get the much
进行处理 而不再涉及这个方向 这样一来得到的边界会更加锐利
sharper. We still see that we have removed noise
我们消除了对象内部的噪点
inside the object, inside the grey matter of these MRI picture of the brain, we see
就是这张脑部MRI(核磁共振图像)中灰色的部分 可以看出
that this is much smoother, that we are still preserving the boundaries very,
现在的图像平滑多了 但同时边界仍然十分明晰
very, nicely. The difference between these two is here,
这就是两者的区别
we have what we have marked here with red background, is isotropic diffusion, heat
上红色背景的是各向同性扩散 热量方程
equation. We actually already talked about it that
之前我们已经提到过
we're going to to derive it in the next slide using Calculus of variations.
我们将使用变分法对方程进行推导
Here, we have added isotropic before we take the second derivative which is a
在求二阶导数之前已经加上了各向同性
divergence. I have to basically remind you that the
二阶导数是分散函数 在此提醒大家
Laplacian of the image is the divergence of the gradient.
图像的拉普拉斯算子是梯度的分散函数
And we are ready to define gradient and the divergence in the previous slides.
此前已经学过如何定义梯度和分散函数
So, before we take it as here, we introduce a function in between here.
在我们计算梯度和分散函数之前 我们先引入一个函数
This is a very similar function as the one that we used for active counters.
这个函数与之前用作计数器的函数十分类似
It's, for example, one over the gradient, we are going to see that in the next
比如这个函数可能是基于梯度的函数 我们在下一张中将看到
slide. So, a function is going to say,
这个函数可能会说
wait a second. Don't diffuse if there is a strong
等一下 如果某处梯度变化巨大 则在此处
gradient. Stop the diffusion.
停止扩散过程
And that's why there is diffusion in certain directions when there is not a
这使得扩散只能在梯度没有巨大变化的某些方向上进行
strong gradient. And there is no diffusion or reduced
而在出现边界 也就是梯度出现巨大变化的某些方向上
diffusion where there is a strong gradient, meaning across edges.
不会进行平均或只有减弱的平均
And that's where we get very sharp boundaries.
这些方向 也是我们保留锐利边界的地方
We preserve them while at the same time, regularizing inside the objects.
我们在对对象内部进行平滑降噪的同时保留了清晰锐利的边界
And that's what we want. These equations are the results of
这正是我们想要的 这些方程是变分法推导出的
Calculus of variations. So, if we basically define any function
任意定义一个关于
of the gradient, so here,
梯度的函数
this is what we saw the last time that we were basically taking functions of u or
这是之前见过的 取u或u的导数的函数
derivatives of u. And basically, the gradient is the
梯度是图像的导数
derivative of the image and rho here takes the role of f.
rho在这里相当于f
So, we take any function of the magnitude of the gradient.
定义任意关于梯度大小的函数
If we compute the Euler-Lagrange, this is what we get.
使用Euler-Lagrange方程展开 得到这个式子
That's the Euler-Lagrange of that equation if we follow exactly the formula
这是这个式子的Euler-Lagrange变换 如果你严格按照之前视频中的步骤
that we show in the previous video. And remember, the partial differential
来做的话 记住 偏微分方程是通过对图像进行
equation is obtained by deforming the image equal to the Euler-Lagrange.
Euler-Lagrange变形得到的
And then, when this doesn't change anymore, we have
当这个不再变化时
solved the Euler-Lagrange and we have obtained may be only local, but at least
就解出了Euler-Lagrange方程 得到了 可能仅是局部的
we obtained that minimizer of this functional.
使得方程值最小的解
So, once again, this is just by doing the Euler-Lagrange that we learned in the
再重复一遍 仅进行之前视频中讲过的Euler-Lagrange变换
previous video. We just pick a couple of examples of this
用几个具体的rho函数为例
raw function to show how nice this is. For example, let us consider rho of a to
例如 rho(a)=a^2
be a squared. So here, I am trying to minimize the
要最小化的是
magnitude of the gradient squared. And then, the Euler-Lagrange,
梯度大小的平方 然后是Euler-Lagrange变换
so ir rho of a is a squared, then rho prime is 2a,
rho(a)=a^2 rho‘等于2a
okay? So, instead of rho prime, I have to put
将式子中的rho‘替换为2 x rho的自变量
two times whatever is inside rho, which is the gradient,
也就是梯度
okay? So basically, have here, and then the
得到这个式子
Euler-Lagrange that I get is, the Euler-Lagrange equation is pie t,
Euler-Lagrange方程为I(t)
this is this, equal to divergence of rho prime, basically 2a.
等于rho‘ 也就是2a的分散函数
Let me ignore the two, it's just scale. So, a time, we mean, replace the
可以忽略2 因为它仅仅是个标量 所以a
gradient, okay?
乘以
a is taking basically the position of the gradient, the absolute magnitude of the
a在此处为梯度大小的绝对值
gradient, sorry. And this is this part.
这是这部分
So, this part stays and this part is rho prime.
这部分不变 这部分等于rho‘
Now, these two cancel and I go divergence of basically the gradient and this is the
分子分母相同消除 式子变为自变量为梯度的分散函数
Laplacian. For this function, the Euler-Lagrange is
也就是拉普拉斯算子 在这个例子中 Euler-Lagrange
basically the heat flow and that's isotropic.
方程与热量方程一致 是各向同性
That's basically smoothing it in an isotropic fashion,
是各向同性平滑
okay? So, that's the Euler-Lagrange of the
梯度大小绝对值的平方
square of the absolute value of the magnitude, we get the regular heat flow,
Euler-Lagrange方程 也是一般的热量方程
the Isotropic Diffusion, diffusion all around.
是各向同性扩散
Let's just pick another example that is really, really, really interesting.
让我们再来看一个非常有趣的例子
Let's just pick, for example, a function that basically, rho of a = a, okay?
令rho(a)=a
Just itself, we could take the absolute value of a but let's just leave that
函数等于自变量 也可以使它等于a的绝对值 但我们现在
technicality aside for a second. Then, rho prime is one,
不纠缠这些细节 rho‘＝1
okay? So, I'm basically going to try to
也就是说 现在是对
minimize the absolute value of the gradient,
梯度的绝对值求最小值
not the gradient square, the absolute value of the gradient
不再是对梯度平方求最小值了 是梯度的绝对值
without putting it to the square. And then, what do I get as the
而不是平方 这个式子的
Euler-Lagrange equation of that? So, rho prime is now a constant.
Euler-Lagrange方程是什么 rho‘现在是常数
So, I go, divergence of gradient normalized by the gradient.
现在变为被梯度自身正则化的梯度的分散函数
So, I didn't get anymore the heat flow. I got this normalization factor that is
我得到的不再是热量方程 而是一个正则因子
saying, wait a second, if the grand is very high, you are one over the gradient
这个因子说 等一下  如果梯度太陡 你就跨过了梯度
so slow down and try to preserve those edges.
先缓一缓 从而把这些边界保留下来
So, this is one example of an Isotropic Diffusion.
这是各向异性扩散的一个例子
It's actually called the total variation. Total [SOUND] variation, that's basically
这方法被成为全变差 (Total variation）也就是这个式子
the name of this equation. And now, I want you to think for a
现在我想让你们思考一下
second, what is this? We learned it a couple of videos ago.
这部分是什么 在前面的视频中学过
This is curvature of the level lines of the image I.
这是图像i中水平线的曲率
We actually use it as a genetic function. We use it phi, in that case, or, or phi,
之前我们把它作为泛函数使用 当时我们使用的是函数phi
we use this in that case. Now, this is the curvature of every level
这是图像中每条水平线的曲率
line of the image. So, we are basically considering the
我们将图像抽象为一个平面
image as a surface and we are deforming the image, we are doing an Isotropic
对图像进行变形 对图像使用各向异性扩散
Diffusion of the image in such a way that basically it's moving according to the
扩散的方向是图像中水平线的曲率
curvature of the level lines and that's getting us an Isotropic Diffusion.
得到的就是各向异性扩散
This is an extremely interesting connection.
这个联系非常有趣
We talked about curve evolution, we talked about curvature type of motions.
我们讲过曲线演化 也讲过基于曲率的运动
This is a curvature type of motion. That basically the image is moving based
这就是其中一种 大体上 图像是沿着水平线的曲率
on curvature of the level lines and that's, we don't really care about the
来移动的 我们并不关心
level lines or we didn't derive this equation from the level lines, we derived
图像中的水平线 方程也不是从水平线推导出来的
it from the Euler-Lagrange of the total variation.
我们是使用全变差的Euler-Lagrange变换推导出方程的
But we connected between the both, between both of them moving according to
但它们却被联系起来 联系点是无论是按照水平线的曲率
curvature type of equations and moving curvature of the level lines and moving
还是按照Euler-Lagrange方程来移动
according to the Euler-Lagrange. The curvature of what?
它们都是按照曲率方程来移动 什么的曲率？
The curvature of the level lines of the image.
是图像中水平线的曲率
A very interesting connection between curve evolution, level set, and Calculus
这是曲线演化 水平线和变分法之间一个饶有兴味的联系
of variation, and that gives us a very, very nice equation for Anisotropic
这个联系本身也是各向异性扩散的一个非常美妙的方程
Diffusion. And this basically is one of the most
这也是在图像处理中
famous examples of the use of Calculus of variations in image processing.
使用变分法的著名例子之一
What's left in this week is to conclude the week in the next video with a bit
我们将在下个视频中对这周进行小结
more of active contours, one of the main clients of curve
将涉及一点活动轮廓模型 也是使用曲线
evolution and Calculus of variations as we have discussed in the past and that's
演化和变分法的主战场 就像我们以前讨论过的那样
we're going to see in the next video. Thank you very much.
这些将在下个视频中看到 非常感谢
I'm looking forward to that. Thank you.
非常期待 谢谢